# **Dellarontay A. Readus**

### dellreadus@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://dellarontayr.github.io/

#### **Professional Summary**

As a **Stanford University educated senior level Software Engineer** who has been working with various languages and advanced systems **professionally for the past 7 years**, I have the ability to pick up new development pipelines and begin contributing immediately. I'm excited to use my professional experience in large scale applications from **Microsoft** and **The Stanford High Performance Computing Center** to create solutions and tools for new organizations as a **Software Engineer** and **Full-Stack Software as a Service Developer**.

#### **Education and Training**

- Stanford University Computer Science B.S. Candidate in Stanford, CA
- Proficient Coding languages: ReactJS, Angular, Python3, C++, C#, C, AWS, TypeScript, Java, Keras
- Concentration in Machine Learning and AI, including creation of a Mario ML Model in OpenAI Gym.
- Valedictorian, Senior Vice-President, President of NHS at Melrose High School Class of 2015 in Memphis, TN

#### **Work History**

### **CodeCrew Code School Teaching Assistant** in **Memphis, TN** -- September 2021 to current:

- \* Taught concepts to and assisted students with the following courses provided by CodeCrew:
  - ➤ Code 102: Introduction to Software Development, Code 201: Foundation of Software Development, and Code 401: Advanced Software Development in Python

## <u>Stanford</u> HPCC Senior Software Engineer in Stanford, CA -- June 2018 to April 2021:

- Directed the crafting of successful D.O.D. proposals for Shepard and Yellowstone systems valued at over \$15M
- Deployed hybrid cluster made from Shepard and Yellowstone in less than a month from system retrieval.
- Debugged GitLab enabling Continuous Integration on U.S. Gov systems (LLNL, Sandia) for PSAAP III projects.

### Chief Technology Officer of Mookie Dough LLC in Stanford, CA-- January 2017 to December 2018

- Full Stack engineer building and maintaining large scale MEAN; MongoDB, ExpressJS, Angular, NodeJs; stack web application.
- Deployed web and test applications using AWS services including: EC2 servers, Elastic Beanstalk, IAM management, Route 53, S3 servers, VPC, Elastic Load Balancing, and Scalable Deployment.
- Bootstrapped and created a modern e-commerce web application to support business deliverables and efficiency.
- Worked with MongoDB database to store and present key user data and telemetry.

## Stanford HPCC Software Engineer in Stanford, CA-- September of 2015 to June 2018

- Installed high performance computing clusters for tasks in parallel programming (MVAPICH, OpenMPI), CFD
- Lead the development of bash scripts and Docker containers to ease the use of clusters for researchers.
- Instantiated Linux-based KNL and KNC Intel XEON nodes to run diagnostics and diagramming on hardware components using programs like Intel Trace Analyzer and Intel Cluster Edition Parallel Studio.
- Presented key open source high performance computing platforms and environments at HPCC Conferences.

# Microsoft Software Engineer Intern in Redmond, WA- Summer of 2017: Presented project to manager of eng group

- Built an application to improve security measures for Microsoft code repositories' main development pipeline
- Created and configured new C# projects including internal NuGet and Microsoft libraries that will be stored for future developer usage.
- Assessed Microsoft Visual Studio Online (MVSO) and VSTS for high security, high-volatility collaboration including mandatory pull requests to main production branches.
- Enabled communication between teams to consolidate resources for a solution optimized for our target customers.

#### Microsoft Explore Intern in Redmond, WA -- Summer of 2016: Presented project to manager of engineering group

- Created a timeline to execute necessary debugging steps in the building of a company-wide onboarding tool while transitioning between program manager, quality control, and development roles.
- Refined user stories for future updates of the system after the internship is over for longevity.
- ❖ Built YAML front-end interface for Jumpstart onboarding web application.